When building a complex
application using an LLM, one of the
important but sometimes
tricky steps is how do you
evaluate how well
your application is doing?
Is it meeting some accuracy criteria?
And also, if you decide
to change your implementation,
maybe swap in a different LLM,
or change the strategy
of how you use a vector database or
something else to retrieve chunks,
or change some other
parameters of your system,
how do you know if you're
making it better or worse? In
this video, Harrison
will dive into some
frameworks on how to
think about evaluating a LLM-based application,
as well
as some tools to help
you do that.
These applications are really
chains and sequences of
a lot of different steps.
And so honestly, part of the first
thing that you should
do is just understand
what exactly is going
in and coming out of each step.
And so some of the tools can really
just be thought of
as visualizers or debuggers
in that vein.
But it's often really useful to
get a more holistic picture on a lot
of different data points
of how the model is doing. And
one way to do that is
by looking at things by eye. But
there's also this really cool
idea of using language models themselves
and chains themselves
to evaluate other
language models, and other
chains, and other
applications. And we'll dive a
bunch into that as well.
So, lots of cool topics,
and I find that with a lot of
development shifting towards prompting-based
development, developing
applications using LLMs, this
whole workflow evaluation process
is being rethought. So, lots
of exciting concepts in this video.
Let's dive in.
Alright, so let's
get set up with evaluation. First, we
need to have the chain
or the application that we're going
to evaluate in the first place.
And we're going to use the
document question answering chain
from the previous lesson.
So we're
going to import everything we need.
We're going to load the same
data that we were using.
We're going to create that
index with one line.
And then we're going to create the
retrieval QA chain by
specifying the language model, the
chain type, the retriever, and
then the verbosity that we're going
to print out.
So we've got this application, and
the first thing we need to do is
we need to really
figure out what are
some data points that
we want to evaluate it on.
And so there's
a few different methods that we're going
to cover for doing this.
The first is the most simple,
which is basically we're
going to come up with
data points that we think
are good examples ourselves.
And so to do that, we can just look
at some of the data and come up
with example questions and
then example ground truth
answers that we can
later use to evaluate.
So if we look at
a few of the documents here,
we can kind of get a sense of what's
going on inside them. It
looks like the first one, there's this
pullover set, there's this in
the second one, there's this jacket, it
has a bunch of details about all of
them.
And from these details,
we can create some
example query and answer pairs.
So the first one,
we can ask a simple,
"Does the Cozy Comfort
Pullover Set have side pockets?".
And we can see by
looking above that it does, in fact,
have some side pockets in it.
And then for the second one,
we can see that this
jacket is from a certain collection,
the DownTek collection.
And so we can ask the question,
"What collection is this jacket from?"
And have the answer be,
"The DownTek collection". So here we've
created two examples.
But this doesn't
really scale that well. It
takes a bit of time
to look through each example
and figure out what's going
on. And so is there a way that
we can automate it?
And one of the
really cool ways that
we think we can automate it is with
language models themselves.
So we have a chain in
LangChain that can do exactly that.
So we can import
the QA generation chain.
And this will take
in documents and it
will create a question
answer pair from each document.
It'll do this using a
language model itself. So
we need to create this
chain by passing in the
Chat OpenAI language model.
And then from there,
we can create a bunch of examples.
And so we're going to use the
apply and parse method
because this is applying
an output parser to
the result because we
want to get back
a dictionary that has
the query and answer pair, not
just a single string.
And so now, if we look at
what exactly is returned here,
we can see a query,
and we can see an answer, and let's
check the document that this is
a question and answer for, and
we can see that it's asking
what the weight of this is, we can
see that it's taking the
weight from here, and look at
that! We just generated
a bunch of question-answer pairs. We didn't
have to write it
all ourselves. Saves us a bunch of
time, and we can do more
exciting things. And so now, let's go
ahead and add these examples into the examples
that we already created.
So, we got these examples now,
but how exactly do we evaluate what's
going on?
The first thing we want
to do is just run
an example through the chain,
and take a look at the output it
produces.
So here we pass in a query,
and we get back an answer. But,
this is a little
bit limiting in terms
of what we can see that's
actually happening inside the chain.
What is the actual prompt that's
going into the language model? What
are the documents that it retrieves?
If this were a more
complex chain with multiple
steps in it, what
are the intermediate results?
It's oftentimes not enough to
just look at the final answer to understand
what is or could
be going wrong in the chain.
And to help with that, we have a fun
little util in LangChain called
"langchain.debug".
And so if we set "langchain.debug =
True", and we now rerun
the same example as above.
We can see that
it starts printing out
a lot more information.
And so if we look at what exactly it's
printing out, we can see that it's diving
down first into the
retrieval QA chain.
And then it's going down into a
stuff documents chain. And
so as mentioned, we're using
the stuff method.
And now it's entering the LLM chain, where
we have a few different inputs. So
we can see the original
question is right there.
And now we're
passing in this context. And
we can see that this context is created
from a bunch of
the different documents that we've retrieved.
And so when doing question answering,
oftentimes when a wrong result is
returned, it's not necessarily the language
model itself that's messing
up. It's actually the
retrieval step that's messing up.
And so taking a
really close look at
what exactly the question is,
and what exactly the context is,
can help debug what's going wrong.
We can then step
down one more level
and see exactly what
is entering the language model,
Chat OpenAI itself.
And so here we can
see the full prompt that's
passed in. So we've got
a system message.
We've got the description of
the prompt that's used. And so
this is the prompt that the question answering
chain is using under
the hood, which we
actually haven't even looked
at until now.
And so we can
see the prompt printing out,
"Use the following pieces of
context to answer the user's
question. If you don't know
the answer, just say
that you don't know, don't try to make
up an answer." And then we see
a bunch of the context as
inserted before, and then we see
a human question, which is the question
that we asked it. We can also see
a lot more information
about the actual return
type. So rather than just
a string, we get back a
bunch of information like
the "token_usage", so the "prompt_tokens", the
"completion_tokens", "total_tokens", and the "model_name".
And this can be really useful
to track the tokens that you're
using in your chains or calls to language
models over time and
keep track of the
total number of tokens, which
corresponds very closely to
the total cost.
And because this is
a relatively simple chain,
we can now see that the final response,
"The Cozy Comfort Pullover Set,
Stripe does have side pockets.",
is getting bubbled up
through the chains and
getting returned to the user. So we've
just walked through how to
look at and debug what's going
on with a single input
to this chain.
But what about all
the examples we created?
How are we going to evaluate those?
Similarly to when creating them,
one way to do it would be manually.
We could run the chain over all the
examples, then look at the outputs,
and try to figure out what's
going on, whether it's correct, incorrect, partially
correct. Similar to
creating the examples, that starts
to get a little bit
tedious over time.
And so let's
go back to our favorite solution. Can
we ask a language model to do it? First,
we need to create predictions
for all the examples. Before
doing that, I'm actually
going to turn off
the debug mode in order to just not
print everything out onto
the screen.
And then I'm going to create
predictions for all
the different examples. And
so I think we
had seven examples total, and
so we're going to loop through this
chain seven times, getting a
prediction for each one.
Now that we've got these examples, we
can think about evaluating them.
So we're going to import the QA, question
answering, eval chain. We
are going to create this
chain with a language model, because
again, we're going to be using a
language model to help
do the evaluation.
And then we're
going to call evaluate on this chain. We're
going to pass in examples
and predictions, and we're going to
get back a bunch of
graded outputs. And so, in order to
see what exactly is going on
for each example, we're going to loop
through them.
We're
going to print out the question, and
again, this
was generated by a language model.
We're
going to print out the real answer, and
again, this was also generated by
a language model when it had the whole
document in front of it, and
so it could generate
a ground truth answer.
We're going to print out
the predicted answer, and
this is generated by a
language model when it's doing
the QA chain, when it's doing the
retrieval with the embeddings and the
vector databases, passing that into
a language model, and then trying
to guess the predicted
answer.
And then we're
also going to print out the grade, and
again, this
is also generated by a
language model when it's asking
the eval chain to grade what's going on
and whether it's correct or incorrect.
And so, when we loop through all
these examples and print them out,
we can see those in detail for each
example.
And looks like here
it got everything correct. This is a
relatively simple retrieval problem,
so that is reassuring.
So let's look at the first example. The
question here is, "Does
the Cozy Comfort Pullover
Set have side pockets?". The
real answer, and
we created this, is "Yes".
The predicted answer,
which the language model produced was,
"The Cozy Comfort Pullover Set,
Stripe does have side pockets".
And so we can understand
that this is a correct answer.
And actually the language
model does as well,
and it grades it correct.
But let's think about why we actually
need to use the language
model in the first place.
These two strings
are actually nothing alike.
They're very different. One's really
short, one's really long. I don't even
think, yes doesn't appear anywhere in this
string. So if we were to
try to do some string
matching, or exact matching, or even
some regexes here,
it wouldn't know what to
do. They're not the same thing. And that
shows off the importance of
using the language model to do
evaluation here. You've got these answers,
which are arbitrary strings.
There's no single one
truth string that is the
best possible answer. There's
many different variants. And
as long as they have
the same semantic meaning,
they should be graded as
being similar. And that's what
a language model helps with, as opposed
to just
doing exact matching.
This difficulty in
comparing strings is
what makes evaluation
of language models so hard in
the first place.
We're
using them for these really open-ended tasks,
where they're asked to
generate text. This hasn't really
been done
before, as models until recently
weren't really good enough to
do this. And so a lot of
the evaluation metrics that
did exist up to
this point just aren't
good enough. And we're having
to invent new ones, and
invent new heuristics for doing so.
And the most interesting and most popular
of those heuristics at the moment
is actually using a language model
to do the evaluation. This finishes
the evaluation lesson, but one
last thing I want to
show you is the LangChain Evaluation Platform. This
is a way to
do everything that we just did
in the notebook, but
persisted and show it in a
UI. And so let's check it out. Here,
we can see that we have a session.
We called it, deeplearningai.
And we can see here that we've
actually persisted all the
runs that we ran
in the notebook. And
so this is a good
way to track the inputs
and outputs at a high level.
But it's also a really good
way to see what
exactly is going on underneath. So
this is the same
information that was printed
out in the notebook
when we turned on
debug mode.
But it's just visualized in a UI in a
little bit of a nicer way.
And so we can see the inputs to
the chain and the
outputs to the chain at each step.
And then we can
click further and further
down into the chain
and see more and
more information about what
is actually getting passed in.
And so if we go all
the way down to the bottom,
we can now see what's
getting passed exactly to
the chat model. We've got
the system message here.
We've got the human question here. We've
got the response from the
chat model here. And we've got some
output metadata. One other thing
that we've added here is
the ability to add these examples to a
data set. So if you remember,
when creating those data
sets of examples at the
start, we created them partially
by hand, partially with a language
model.
Here, we can add it to a data set
by clicking on this little button.
And we now have the
input query and the output results.
And so we can create a data set.
We can call it deep learning.
And then we can start
adding examples to this data set.
And so again, getting back to
the original thing that we tackled
at the beginning of the lesson,
we need to create
these data sets so that we can do
evaluation. This is a really
good way to have
this just running in the background.
And then add to the example
data sets over time and start
building up these examples that you
can start using for evaluation and
have this flywheel
of evaluation start turning.